# Richard Kennedy

# Frontend developer







#### **PROFILE**

A frontend developer Intern at Mobiento / Deloitte Digital and soon to be a Frontend development graduate from Hyper Island in Stockholm, Sweden. My personality can be described in three words: passionate, curious and determined. I love to be challenged and have a strong ability to work in teams and independently, but most of all I am eager to learn and look for any opportunity to better my skills as a developer. I am now looking to secure a junior frontend position to kick-start my career and become the best web-developer I can be.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend Developer Intern

Mobiento / Deloitte Digital

Sep 2022 - Present, Stockholm

Building an Unsplash clone as my intern task. And continuing to really deep dive into React | Typescript | Unit Testing | Bitbucket

# Frontend Development

Aug 2021 - Present, Stockholm

Currently studying frontend development at Hyper Island. Project-based learning both individually and in teams. Adapting an agile mindset to my development process and learning to create beautiful, functional, practical and all in between - web applications.

# Industrial/Commercial Electrician

Norrsken Elinstallationer

Jan 2016 - Aug 2021 - 5 years, Stockholm

# **Supervisor Construction Electrician**

Civmec Engineering & Goodline electrical

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 - 1 year, Port Hedland, Australia

# Apprentice Electrician

Changeovers PTY LTD

Jan 2011 - jan 2015 - 4 years, Perth, Australia

## **CONTACT**

Richardgrahamkennedy@gmail.com

+46 73 833 29 99

### Education

Frontend development Full-time Diploma

Hyper Island

2021 - 2023 Stockholm, Sweden

#### **CERTIFICATE III in Electrotechnology**

Electrician

North Metropolitan TAFE 2011 - 2014, Perth Australia

# **Industry Knowledge**

Product Design & development Agile development process Working in teams SEO & Accessibility Wireframing Prototyping

### **Skills**

Design Research

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Javascript, Phaser.JS, React.JS, Figma, GitHub, MongoDB, Typescript, Unit-testing

#### **Hobbies**

Coding, Surfing, Snowboarding, Coffee, Interior design, Fashion, MUSIC

# Language

English (professional)
Swedish (learning)

### Reference

Will happily provide on request

# Richard Kennedy

# Frontend developer

# **Professional Highlights**

2022 -

Unsplash Clone - (React / Typescript / Tailwind / Jest )

Re-creating Unsplash using the Unsplash API.

This project comes with a clean UI that features a search-bar, the classic unsplash masonry grid layout for my image gallery, a category list that routes dynamically, placeholders for slow loading and its all responsive. What I learned the most from this project is the importance of testing and how to write a way cleaner code for eg - useContext as oppose to prop drilling, reusing components and functionality.

2022 -

E-commerce Happenings - An experience package

Frontend & Backend (React / Tailwind / JavaScript / MongoDB) I collaborated in a team to build and deploy an e-commerce application that provides experiences such as whale-watching, salsa dancing etc, where all products chosen are taken through a checkout process. I was responsible for the database architecture, developing user friendly interactions, responsiveness, rendering the items in the database and creating an individual information page for selected items.

2022 -

### **3D GAME WHACK-A-CRAB**

Frontend ( JavaScript / A-frame )

I built and deployed a 3D game that I presented at the Hyper Island game conference. I implemented 3D models and a 3D environment into the game that is interactable through the use of JavaScript and A-Frame functionalities.

2022 -

#### **WEBSITE Travel advice**

Frontend & Backend (Next.js / React / Tailwind / MongoDB)

I Built and deployed an application that allowed users to search for a country or city and be given advice on where to eat, stay and discover. I created a database that stores content and uses a frontend stack of Next.js, React and Tailwind to render the content.

2021 -

## **ARCADE GAME Space Invaders**

Frontend ( JavaScript / Phaser.js )

I collaborated in a small team to build and deploy a 2D game using Phaser.js. This game was to be presented to the Hyper Island FED23 class once complete. I was responsible for creating a parallax background, shooter functionality, invaders to disappear on collision and a scoreboard.

